Baalavignesh Arunachalam (He/him)

barunac@gmu.edu | +1 (571) 629-4096 | GitHub: Baalavignesh | LinkedIn: Baalavignesh Arunachalam

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-motivated full-stack developer with a strong background in cloud computing, mobile and web development. More than two years of demonstrated industrial experience on all project scales. Actively participated and won in several hackathons demonstrating teamwork and strong problem-solving skills.

EDUCATION

George Mason University

Master of Science in Computer Science

Virginia, United States August 2024 - Present

PSG College of Technology

5 years integrated M.Sc. Software Systems; CGPA: 7.8/10.0

Coimbatore, India June 2018 - May 2023

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Flutter, C, C++, ASP.NET, Dart, AWS

Skills: React, Angular, Next.js, Node.js, GitHub, Lambda, DevOps, Firebase, MongoDB, SQL

EXPERIENCE

Presidio, Inc.

March 2023 – July 2024

Associate Software Engineer

- Developed internal learning platforms and retro tools using **React** and **AWS** using a serverless approach.
- Worked on projects with technologies involving **WebRTC**, designing **CI/CD** pipelines and mobile app development.

Toast, Inc. June 2022 – July 2022

Software Developer Intern

- Worked with **React** and other AWS services to develop a full-stack application
- Application data is managed and accessed using API Gateway, Lambda and DynamoDB

Zoho Corporation

May 2021 – November 2021

Software Developer Intern

- Created an angular application with state management and authentication for an internal voting system
- Developed an Impact Analyzer tool using Node.js for git commits to track the impacted files

PROJECTS

SkillAgent

Personalized Learning Platform for Workforce Development

- o Developed a full-stack application using **React** and **Node.**js, with **Firebase** for storage and authentication.
- Integrated OpenAI's Assistant and Threads feature and hosted the application on AWS S3 (React) and EC2 (backend).

Secure FileStore

Secure drive to store files and track the version updates

- o Developed a **Python** app that stores files and data with two layers of encryption.
- Stored user info and files in AWS Relational DB and S3 Buckets file versioning helps users track old files.

IMDB Review

Filter the Reviews of IMDB using Sentiment Analysis

- o Utilized Python in Kaggle for text preprocessing, and machine learning with Logistic Regression and Decision Tree.
- Used packages like Matplotlib and Seaborn for data visualization of ROC curve and confusion matrix.

CERTIFICATION & ACHIEVEMENTS

- AWS Certified <u>Solution Architect</u> and <u>Cloud Practitioner</u> issued by Amazon Web Services Training and Certification
- Won Best Prototype Award in Story3 Hackathon conducted by HackerEarth
- Won Honorable Mention in <u>DataPalooza Hackathon</u> conducted by <u>DevPost</u>